digitalfodder.com 2019-09-30

# Privacy Policy

Digital Fodder (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the https://www.digitalfodder.com/ website (the “Service”). This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from https://www.digitalfodder.com/

 **Information Collection and Use**

We collect several different types of information for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

Types of Data Collected

Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Usage Data
  * Cookies
  * Electronic Communication

 **Usage Data**

We may collect information about how the Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

 **Cookies**

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information. Cookies are files with small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies may also include beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. If you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

  * Session cookies. We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  * Preference cookies. We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  * Security cookies. We use Security Cookies for security purposes.

DoubleClick DART Cookie

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on Digital Fodder. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to users based on their visit to Digital Fodder and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and network content privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site.

Use of Data

Digital Fodder may use collected data for various purposes, for example:

  * To provide and maintain the Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide customer care and support
  * To provide analysis or valuable information so that we can improve the Service
  * To monitor the usage of the Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues

Transfer of Data

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to—and maintained on—computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. Your use of the Service followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the [Google Privacy and Terms web page](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

Electronic Communication

The website operates an email newsletter program that is used to inform subscribers about updates, products, and services. All personal details relating to subscriptions are held securely. No personal details are passed on to third parties, companies, or people outside of the Service.

Email marketing campaigns published by the website or its owners contain tracking mechanisms and affiliate links. Subscriber activity is tracked and stored in a database for future analysis and evaluation. For example, subscriber activities include open rates, forwards, clicks, signup dates and times, and so on. The information is used to improve future email campaigns and supply the user with more relevant content based on their activities.

When a user opts into our email list, we collect your name, email address, and IP address, which gives us proof of your signup and consent to receive emails from us. You can unsubscribe from our newsletter by clicking on the unsubscribe link provided at the end of each newsletter or informing us directly via email.

The Service uses [MailerLite](https://www.digitalfodder.com/goto/mailerlite/) for email marketing. They process your data to help us monitor and improve our newsletter. MailerLite’s privacy policy is available at <https://www.mailerlite.com/privacy-policy>.

Affiliate Marketing

[Affiliate marketing](https://www.digitalfodder.com/what-is-affiliate-marketing-how-does-it-work/) and advertising enable me to provide content free of charge and keep the Service online. I make every effort to ensure that advertising is safe, unobtrusive, and as relevant as possible. You can learn more by reading my [privacy policy](https://www.digitalfodder.com/privacy-policy/).

The Service use affiliate links on the site. If you click through and purchase an item, we may earn a commission. Only purchase products and services that can help you achieve your goals. Our opinions are not for sale, and we aim to be objective in our reviews and recommendations.

Advertising

Advertising is one of Digital Fodder’s revenue streams. Therefore, we display advertisements on some of our services (e.g., on certain webpages or in emails).

These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology for the advertisements and links to appear on Digital Fodder. This targeting is always an automated process; none of the information used for targeting is analyzed manually or made available to advertising customers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please go [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

Digital Fodder has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. In some cases, we display advertisements from Google’s AdSense or AdExchange network. You can review Google’s Ads Privacy Policy [here](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/). Furthermore, you can use Google’s Ads Preferences Manager to configure the right ads settings for you.

You can consult the respective privacy policies of any third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. DF’s privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

Disclosure of Data

Digital Fodder may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of Digital Fodder
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

Security of Data

The security of your data is important to us but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100 percent secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Service Providers

We may employ third-party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

Links to Other Sites

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third-party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit. We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third-party sites or services.

Children’s Privacy

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”). We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us: info[[at]]digitalfodder[[dot]]com
